#### $+1\text{-}931\text{-}998\text{-}0046 \ Adam \ Mischke \ mischke@protonmail.com \ github.com/vanities$ catwebm.com

#### Summary

 $\mathbf{S}$ 

0 ng work ethic Full-stack Engineer that learns quickly and is a committed team player. Has 4-years of startup experience working in an agile and TDD environment. Served in the United States Navy as a Network Administrator.

### EDUCATION

### Middle Tennessee State University

Murfreesboro, Tennessee

July 2014 - June 2018

Awards / Memberships: Dean's List 2014-2018, Member of Association of Computing Machinery (ACM), Member of the Upsilon Pi Epsilon Computer Honor Society

### SKILLS

Python, Swift, JavaScript, C++, SQL, Bash, Solidity • Languages:

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science; Minor in Mathematics

• Frameworks: Django, Flask, NodeJS, React, SwiftUI

Tools: Docker, Terraform, GIT, PostgreSQL, Fastlane Platforms: Mac, Linux, Web, iOS, AWS, GCP, Firebase

• Soft Skills: Leadership, Problem Solving, Strong Communication Skills, Time Management

### EXPERIENCE

### FunFunFun Inc. - Gen Z Dating

Remote

Full-stack Engineer (Full-time)

May 2020 - June 2022

- First Engineering Hire: Created a live updating video dating app that integrated with TikTok with over 10,000 users, where users could like, match, and message each-other.
- Backend: Built a Django and GraphQL and a matching algorithm to pair users together with alike parameters.
- Frontend: Deployed a complete SwiftUI app from the ground up to app store. Contributed to an internal Typescript React webpage to police uploaded media and content used by admins.
- $\circ$  **DevOps**: Used GitHub actions to create an CI/CD pipeline for the backend and iOS using fastlane for multiple environments.
- Algorithms: Created a series of Firebase, Firestore, and Google Storage Typescript triggers to create a video processing pipeline that asynchronously cut over 8,000 videos.

#### Coinmine - Crypto Mining Made Easy

Remote

Software Engineer (Full-time - Part-time)

May 2018 - Current

- o First Engineering Hire: Built and maintained mineOS, an Arch Linux-Based Operating System, onto a small form factor computer that mined 6 different cryptocurrencies 24/7 that users could plug and play at home.
- o mineOS: Fabricated the build and deployment tools for distributing mineOS images through a test and build pipeline for over 5,000 miners.
- o Backend: Used Agile, Extreme Programming and Test Driven Development methodologies to deploy, update, and configure a Django based backend with over 8,000 users.
- o DevOps: Arranged and operated analytical, deployment, and pipeline tools such as: CircleCI, Code Climate, Datadog, and Sentry.
- o Frontend: Collaborated with React Native Engineer to build smooth frontend experience between API and Coinmine machine.
- Leadership: Worked with overseas distribution centers to construct and create Standard Operating Procedures (SOP) for assembly and manufacturing.

# Caterpillar Financial Services Corporation

Information Services - Network Team (Intern)

May 2017 - July 2017

- o Leadership: Led research, meetings, and recommended the replacement of a network team application. Worked as liaison between team members and company solutions. Then sought out quote to be implemented into the yearly budget.
- o Problem Solving: Researched and developed a web dashboard that displayed global network information with Python and Flask using a SQL database. Used JavaScript, J-Query, Bootstrap, AJAX, and Google Charts to form a coherent and simple-to-use website. Implemented a search function that integrated with database calls to speed up information flow.

## United States Navy

Fire controlman (FC2) - Computer and Network Technician (Full-time)

July 2008 - July 2014

- Leadership: Efficiently led as work center supervisor, 8 personnel in accomplishing over 1,634 maintenance actions with a 94% maintenance accomplishment rate, managing 372 maintenance checks and repairs.
- Security Clearance: Held a Secret Clearance and handled the Electronic Key Management System, which managed 106 classified software programs and hardware systems.
- Preventative & Corrective Maintenance: Upkeep and corrective maintenance of the Ship's Self Defense System, Open architecture network server and computer systems, Battle Force Tactical Trainer network, and Cooperative Engagement Capability LAN.
- Teamwork: Assisted in the successful overhaul of 3 major system installs with lead engineers to include: Hardware, software, and network installation, troubleshooting to the perfection of the system.

### Projects

- Vison multimedia search engine (NLP, Search Engine, Web Crawlers, Multimedia Processing): (Work in progress) Research oriented, open source, search engine for bringing reverse multimedia search to small & mid scale enterprises. Tech: Python, NodeJS, Intel OpenVino Toolkit, Selenium, TensorFlow (October '18)
- Reinforcement Learning based Traffic Control System (Reinforcement Learning, Computer Vision): AI model to resolve city traffic around 50% faster. Tech: Python, Alibaba Cloud, Raspberry Pi, Arduino, SUMO & OpenCV. (August '18)
- Panorama from Satellite Imagery using Distributed Computing (Distributed Computing, Image Processing): Images clicked using drones, provided by ISRO were stitched together using distributed public compute nodes, effectively bringing down processing time exponentially. Tech: PHP, C++, Java, Python (March '18)
- Drag-n-drop machine learning learning environment (Web Development, Machine Learning): Scratch like tool for implementing machine learning pipelines along with built in tutorial for each concept. Tech: Python, JavaScript (September '18)
- Search Engine and Social Network (Web Development, Web Crawler, Search): Created from scratch a social network and a search engine based on the idea of integrating Facebook and Google. The launched website was among top 1000 websites in India during 2012-2013. Tech: PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, WebSockets, JavaScript, RSS, XML (May '12)